let's answer our numa memory location
quiz in order to
improve performance of a numa machine
the operating system
should really put all data pages that
are mostly accessed by a single core
in
the memory slice local to that core that
will ensure that most of the accesses by
each of the cores are going to the local
memory
which both make sure that accesses will
be quicker than they otherwise would be
and also the network will not be used
for the majority of accesses so this
should be selected if we however put all
data pages ever touched by core n in the
memory slice n then we have a problem
because
for example one core might initialize
all the data and then we put all of the
data in its memory slice and at that
point that memory slice becomes the
bottom line because everybody will be
accessing that slice and the data might
not even fit there so this is not a
correct answer
and then the put the stack pages for
core n in the memory slice n is a very
extreme example of this where really it
will just be the core n that is ever
accessing this data so of course it
should be in its memory slice
so the stack is one of those things that
the operating system can figure out very
easily where to put
some of the other pages are a little bit
more difficult because more than one
core are accessing it and then the
operating system needs to choose a good
location
either because one core is accessing it
more than others
or to put it in a memory module that is
kinda close to all the cores that are
accessing it